Finding Aid for Edward A. Finney photograph collection, ca. 1898-1913
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Edward A. Finney photograph collection circa 1898-1913
Finney, Edward A.
9298 Aa Microcopy; UAs
Soldier during Spanish-American war, officer with the Michigan National Guard. Scenes from the Spanish-American War and of the copper strike in Calumet, Michigan.
1 microfilms
1 folders 17 items
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The original photographs are in the possession of Roger Heiple of South Lyon, Michigan (donor no. 6267 ) who allowed the library to make copies of his collection.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Edward A. Finney of Jackson County, Michigan, was a private in the 31st Michigan Infantry, Company D, later a lieutenant in Company D of the First Michigan Independent Battalion, Michigan National Guard, and a captain in Company M, First Infantry Michigan National Guard.
The collection consists of a microfilm copy (with selective contact prints) of photographs accumulated by Edward A. Finney during the period of his military service during the Spanish-American War and as a participant with the Michigan National Guard during the copper strike in Calumet, Michigan, 1913-1914.
Subjects:
Calumet (Mich.); Copper Miners' Strike, Mich., 1913-1914.; Michigan. National Guard.; Military camps.; Miners' strikes.; Strikes.; United States. Army. Michigan Infantry Regiment, 31st (1898-1899). Company D.; Spanish-American War, 1898.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Photographs
  - Spanish-American War
    - Men from Jackson County, Co. D and Co. H, 31st Michigan Infantry at Camp Thomas, Chickamauga Park, Georgia, New Camp August, 1898. Include Clifford Green, Co. H; Charles Oswick, Co. D; Charles Luttenton, Co. H; Harry Stanbridge, Co. D; Christie Stearns, Co. D; George Griest, Co. D; George Maloney, Co. D; Thomas Elliot, Co. D; Fred MaGraw, Co. D. (Reel 1)
      (item no. 1)
    - Rifle Range of the 31st Michigan Infantry, about eight miles from Camp Thomas, Chickamauga Park, Georgia, on Pea Vine Ridge. The picture shows the third Battalion firing at 100 yards. The middle target is Co. D target. (Reel 1)
      (Photo by W.T. Barnum, Adrian, Michigan, No. 22; contact print available)
      (item no. 2)
    - Camp of the 31st Michigan Infantry at Camp Poland, Knoxville, Tennessee September, 1898. Sunday morning inspection. (Reel 1)
      (Photo by W.T. Barnum, Adrian, Michigan, No. 196; contact print available)
      (item no. 3)
    - Grand Review at Camp Poland, Knoxville, Tennessee in honor of General Breckinridge September 15, 1898 at the parade grounds of the 1st Georgia and 31st Michigan. The 31st Michigan is passing in review. (Reel 1)
      (Photo by W.T. Barnum, Adrian, Michigan, No. 203; contact print available)
      (item no. 4)
    - View of the 31st Michigan camp at Savannah, Georgia January 18, 1899 taken at Regimental Parade of the 31st Michigan. Left of Co. H, right of Co. I. (Reel 1)
      (contact print available)
      (item no. 5)
    - Dinner given by the citizens of Savannah, Georgia and members of the 1st Georgia Regiment to the 31st Michigan January 19, 1899. Companies L, E, M, and D being entertained by Co. L, 1st Georgia, "The Jasper Greens" (Reel 1)
      (item no. 6)
    - Loading the U.S. Transport "Chester" at Savannah, Georgia with the 31st Michigan Infantry for Cuba January 25, 1899 (Reel 1)
      (item no. 7)
    - Photo at Amaro, Cuba, near camp of the 31st Michigan February 12, 1899 (Reel 1)
      (item no. 8)
    - The "Minnewaska" afterward the "Thomas" which brought the 31st Michigan from Cuba to America in spring of 1899 (Reel 1)
      (Photo by G.A. Bash, Wilmot, Ohio; contact print available)
      (item no. 9)
  - Michigan National Guard
    - Co. D, First Independent Battalion, Michigan National Guard, Washington's Birthday 1901 (Reel 1)
      (item no. 10)
    - Manistee Company, Camp Bliss August 14, 1901 (Reel 1)
      (item no. 11)
    - State camp, Michigan National Guard, Camp Bliss, Manistee, Michigan August 5-14, 1901. Members of Co. D, Horace M. Foster; Q.M. Sgt.; William N. Neesley; Louis J. Collins, 1st Lieut.; Bert Bishop Morrison; Ralph White; Conrad Eggebreckt; Capt. Burton C. Huickley; Corp. Frank H. Wilcox; E.A. Finney, 2nd Lieut. (Reel 1)
      (item no. 12)
    - Gov. Aaron T. Bliss and staff at Camp Hawley, Manistee, Michigan. Camp of August 11-20, 1902 taken near 3rd Regiment Guard Line, showing sentinel of 3rd Regiment (Reel 1)
      (item no. 13)
    - Manistee Camp 1902 (Reel 1)
      (item no. 14)
    - Camp Young, West Point, Kentucky. October, 1903. Cook tent, Co. D, 1st Independent Battalion, Michigan National Guard. Corp. Noll; Priv. Santer; Q.M. Sgt; Cooks Hurd and Stadelman. (Reel 1)
      (item no. 15)
    - Camp, West Point, Kentucky September 30-October 11, 1903, October 6, 1903. Day after returning from rain. Drying out our clothes (Reel 1)
      (Photo by S.B. Morrell, Detroit; item no. 16)
    - Camp at Harpers Ferry August 5, 1904 (Reel 1)
      (item no. 17)
    - Co. M, 1st Infantry, Michigan National Guard, Ludington, Michigan August, 1905 (Reel 1)
      (item no. 18)
    - Camp at Indianapolis, Indiana August 4-13, 1906 (Reel 1)
      (item no. 19)
    - Camp at Indianapolis August 4-13, 1906. Co. D flooded out (Reel 1)
      (item no. 20)
    - Camp. September 3, 1907 (Reel 1)
      (item no. 21)
    - Battalion officers. 1908 (Reel 1)
      (item no. 22)
    - Co. M, Fist Infantry, Michigan National Guard July 5, 1908. Practice (?) camp of July 3-5, 1908 (Reel 1)
      (item no. 23)
    - Camp, Co. D, 1st Michigan, Calumet, Michigan 1910 (Reel 1)
      (item no. 24)
    - Camp of Instruction, Ft. Benjamin Harrison, Indiana June 20-25, 1910. First tent, Co. D, Provisional Regt. Capt. W.J. Lawrence, Co. B, 1st Infantry; Capt. Alan Lang, Co. H, 1st Infantry; Major John D. Bersey 1st Battalion, 1st Infantry; Capt. John C. Durst, Co. E, 2nd Infantry; Capt. E.A. Finney, Co. M, 1st Infantry. (Reel 1)
      (item no. 25)
    - Camp of Instruction, Ft. Benjamin Harrison, Indiana June 20-25, 1910. Co. D Provisional Regt. Capt. Ingrah. (Reel 1)
      (item no. 26)
    - Co. M, First Infantry. Camp Osborn, Port Huron, Michigan August 9-18, 1911. Picture taken Sunday, August 13, 1911 immediately after inspection. (Reel 1)
      (item no. 27)
    - Ludington, Michigan 1912 (Capt. Finney's tent). (Reel 1)
      (item no. 28)
    - Ludington, Michigan 1912(Soldiers and families before tent of Cant. Finney, small group) (Reel 1)
      (item no. 29)
    - Ludington, Michigan 1912(Soldiers and families before tent of Capt. Finney, large group.) (Reel 1)
      (item no. 30)
  - Co. M. First Infantry. Copper Strike, Calumet, Michigan 1913
    - Postcards by C.E. Beckwith, Norvell, Michigan
      - Soldiers posed before tent (Reel 1)
        (item no. 31)
      - Soldiers at case before tent (Reel 1)
        (item no. 32)
      - Tents pitched before house and armory (Reel 1)
        (item no. 33)
      - Tents pitched before house (Reel 1)
        (item no. 34)
      - Soldiers marching near tent (Reel 1)
        (item no. 35)
    - Postcard July 25, 1913 starting for Calumet (Reel 1)
      (item no. 36)
    - Postcard, dated Calumet, Michigan August 1, 1913 to Mrs. E.A. Finney, Jackson, Michigan. "This is our Co. waiting orders to make camp Sunday, A.M. July 27. You can see me at extreme right talking to Major Puck. E.A.F. All quiet." (Reel 1)
      (item no. 37)
    - Postcard, dated Calumet, Michigan August 8, 1913 to Burnett Finney, Jackson, Michigan. "This is where we get our supper. Can you see Uncle Lawrence and Daddy?..." (Reel 1)
      (item no. 38)
    - Co. M, 1st Infantry at Calumet August, 1913 (Reel 1)
      (item no. 39)
    - Postcard, unidentified, probably at Calumet 1913 (street with pickets? and posted guardsman.) (Reel 1)
      (item no. 40)
    - Postcard, unidentified. Probably at Calumet 1913 (soldiers and civilians near station) (Reel 1)
      (item no. 41)
    - Postcard, unidentified. Probably at Calumet 1913 (acrobatic stances) (Reel 1)
      (item no. 42)
    - Co. 14, 1st Infantry, from Jackson, Michigan at Calumet 1913 (Reel 1)
      (item no. 43)
    - Calumet, Michigan 1913 (Reel 1)
      (Same building as item no. 38; contact print available)
      (item no. 44)
  - Other Photographs
    - Capt. E.A. Finney snapshot (Reel 1)
      (item no. 45)
    - Capt. E.A. Finney, New York March 15, 1913 (portrait. (Reel 1)
      (item no. 46)
    - Camp at Island Lake? (Reel 1)
      (Photo by E. J. Stone, Dexter; contact print available)
      (item no. 47)
    - Co. D, First Independent Battalion, Manistee, Michigan undated (Reel 1)
      (item no. 48)
    - Camp at Manistee, Michigan. undated (Reel 1)
      (Photo by Anton Lotz, No. 8)
      (item no. 49)
    - Unidentified group photo (about 40 men) (Reel 1)
      (item no. 50)
    - Unidentified group photo (3 men) (Reel 1)
      (item no. 51)
    - Unidentified group photo (18 men before tents) (Reel 1)
      (item no. 52)
    - Unidentified group photo (11 men with sign: The Happy Hooligans) (Reel 1)
      (item no. 53)
    - Unidentified group photo (soldiers with dog cart) (Reel 1)
      (item no. 54)
    - Gardner's Red Necks. Twelfth Annual Reunion, May 17, Lansing. Michigan circa 1910 (Reel 1)
      (Photo by Bovee)
      (item no. 55)
    - Co. D, First Michigan Infantry 1916 (Reel 1)
      (item no. 56)